<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AWS Chatbot &amp; Slack Integration on Chatbot Workshop</title>
    <link>/slack/</link>
    <description>Recent content in AWS Chatbot &amp; Slack Integration on Chatbot Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/slack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup Dev Env with Cloud9</title>
      <link>/slack/setup-dev-env/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/slack/setup-dev-env/</guid>
      <description>Login to your AWS Account, make sure you are in the North Virginia (us-east-1) region
 Click on Services Drop down, type Cloud9. Click on Create environment.
 Type: chatbot-workshop for Name. Click on Next step.
 Leave all settings default. Click on Next step. Then click Create environment.  It will take about 3-5 minutes to create your Cloud9 environment.
 We&amp;rsquo;ll deploy a simple REST API service. From your Cloud9, open a new Terminal (+ icon next to Welcome tab) and run:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create SNS Topics</title>
      <link>/slack/sns-topics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/slack/sns-topics/</guid>
      <description> Make sure you are still in the us-east-1 (North Virginia) region.
  Click on Services Drop down, type SNS and select Simple Notification Service.
 Click on Topics on left-side menu. Click Create Topic.
 Name: cloudformation-alert
 Under Access Policy, select Everyone for both sections. Click Create topic.  Repeat the above steps to create another topic for cloudwatch-alert.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure AWS Chatbot</title>
      <link>/slack/configure-aws-chatbot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/slack/configure-aws-chatbot/</guid>
      <description>Click on Services Drop down, type Chatbot and select AWS Chatbot. Select Slack as the chat client from the dropdown. Click on Configure client.  Create a new Slack workspace or Login with your existing Slack workshop where you have Admin access to create channels.
 Once Logged into Slack, click on Allow AWS Chatbot to access your Slack workspace  Go to Slack, create 2 public channels: cloudformation-alert, cloudwatch-alarm.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>