<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chatbot Workshop</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Chatbot Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup Dev Env with Cloud9</title>
      <link>/slack/setup-dev-env/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/slack/setup-dev-env/</guid>
      <description>Login to your AWS Account, make sure you are in the North Virginia (us-east-1) region
 Click on Services Drop down, type Cloud9. Click on Create environment.
 Type: chatbot-workshop for Name. Click on Next step.
 Leave all settings default. Click on Next step. Then click Create environment.  It will take about 3-5 minutes to create your Cloud9 environment.
 We&amp;rsquo;ll deploy a simple REST API service. From your Cloud9, open a new Terminal (+ icon next to Welcome tab) and run:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create SNS Topics</title>
      <link>/slack/sns-topics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/slack/sns-topics/</guid>
      <description> Make sure you are still in the us-east-1 (North Virginia) region.
  Click on Services Drop down, type SNS and select Simple Notification Service.
 Click on Topics on left-side menu. Click Create Topic.
 Name: cloudformation-alert
 Under Access Policy, select Everyone for both sections. Click Create topic.  Repeat the above steps to create another topic for cloudwatch-alert.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure AWS Chatbot</title>
      <link>/slack/configure-aws-chatbot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/slack/configure-aws-chatbot/</guid>
      <description>Click on Services Drop down, type Chatbot and select AWS Chatbot. Select Slack as the chat client from the dropdown. Click on Configure client.  Create a new Slack workspace or Login with your existing Slack workshop where you have Admin access to create channels.
 Once Logged into Slack, click on Allow AWS Chatbot to access your Slack workspace  Go to Slack, create 2 public channels: cloudformation-alert, cloudwatch-alert.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Package &amp; Deploy Lambda using SAM</title>
      <link>/rest-api/deploy-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/rest-api/deploy-service/</guid>
      <description>Go back to Cloud9 service.
 Create the S3 repo to store SAM artifact. Since the S3 repo name must be globally unique, please postfix with your username
aws s3api create-bucket --bucket chatbot-workshop-[your-username]  Make sure you are in the rest-api directory
cd ~/environment/lambda-example/rest-api/  Package the template. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to replace chatbot-workshop-[your-username] with your actual S3 bucket name.
sam package --output-template-file template_packaged.yaml --s3-bucket chatbot-workshop-[your-username]  Deploy Lambda using SAM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CloudFormation Notification</title>
      <link>/rest-api/cloudformation-notification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/rest-api/cloudformation-notification/</guid>
      <description> Go to CloudFormation service. Click on Stack chatbot-workshop-rest-api-lambda.
 Click on Update.
 Leave Step 1 and 2 as default, click Next.
 At Step 3, scroll down and click on Notification options. Select SNS: cloudformation-alert. Click Next.  At Step 4 Review, check the acknowledge box and click Update stack.  Now everytime you makes changes to your Stack, you will see alert in your Slack.   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create CloudWatch Alarm</title>
      <link>/rest-api/create-cw-alarm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/rest-api/create-cw-alarm/</guid>
      <description>Go to CloudWatch service. Click on Alarms on the left hand side. Click on Create alarm button.
 Click Select Metric button. Look for Lambda and click on it. Clik on By Function Name. Select the one starts with prefix chatbot-workshop- and the Metric Name is Errors. Then click Select metric.  Update the Metric panne to set Statistic: Sum, Period: 1 minute  Under the Conditions pane, update the value for the threshold value to 1 and click Next.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trigger CloudWatch Alarm</title>
      <link>/rest-api/trigger-cw-alarm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/rest-api/trigger-cw-alarm/</guid>
      <description>Trigger OK Alarm  Go back to Cloud9 service.
 Go into the sample REST API service code:
cd /home/ec2-user/environment/lambda-example/rest-api  Package your Lambda
sam package --output-template-file template_packaged.yaml --s3-bucket chatbot-workshop-[your-username]  Deploy your Lambda. After about 30 seconds, you should see a Slack message in your cloudwatch-alert channel saying everything is OK.
sam deploy --template-file template_packaged.yaml --stack-name chatbot-workshop-rest-api-lambda --capabilities CAPABILITY_IAM   Trigger Error Alarm  Modify the file rest-api.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>